adap.tv 2014-06-25

# 

Adap.tv, a wholly owned subsidiary of AOL Inc., is committed to transparency and accountability in our privacy practices. The following statement describes Adap.tv's Privacy Policy as it relates to the collection, use and disclosure of information Adap.tv receives from users of http://www.adap.tv (this "Site") and Adap.tv's online video advertising platform services (the "Services"). The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of the following:

  * Who Adap.tv is and the services it provides so that you can understand how Adap.tv's business may impact your privacy;
  * What kind of information, including any personally-identifiable information, is collected from you;
  * Who collects the information;
  * How the information is used;
  * With whom the information may be shared;
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information;
  * The security procedures that are in place to protect the information; and How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

##### ABOUT ADAP.TV AND CONSUMERS

Adap.tv provides products and services that help online publishers, agencies, and ad networks manage and deliver online advertising in their online videos. As a consumer, when you see an advertisement before you watch an online video, Adap.tv may help deliver that ad from or for an advertiser to the website that has made the video available to you. Adap.tv also provides a marketplace, where buyers and sellers of online video advertising space can connect and do business.

Adap.tv is not in the business of collecting, using, or selling consumer data; however it does offer tools and technologies to advertisers and publishers that allow them to collect and use user data. This is done primarily to enable these buyers and sellers of online video-advertising space to try and ensure that the audience they desire sees their ads and that the advertising itself is delivered and the performance of the advertising can be analyzed. Types of data that may be used for this purpose range from behavioral or interest-related information to geographical or demographical user data. Adap.tv is an active member of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI") and adheres to the [NAI Code of Conduct](http://www.networkadvertising.org/2013_Principles.pdf).

##### INFORMATION COLLECTED, AND HOW IT IS COLLECTED

Personally-Identifiable Information. Adap.tv does not collect personally-identifiable information in order to help our clients buy, sell, and deliver online video advertising. "Personally-Identifiable Information" means information that alone or when in combination with other information that Adap.tv collects may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you. There may be some opportunities, for example when you use this Site, where you may choose to enter your name, contact information, and other personal details. For example, if you were interested in becoming one of our clients or using our Services you could provide us with contact details through our Site.

Where we collect personally-identifiable information you will have clear notification of what we are doing so that you can choose not to provide it. Non-Personally-Identifiable Information. Non-personally-identifiable information is information that, without additional information, cannot be linked to a specific individual by Adap.tv. Adap.tv may collect non-personally-identifiable information while you are visiting our Site or the website of one of Adap.tv's advertisers or Web publishers (collectively, "Adap.tv Associates"). For example, while providing the Services to website publishers, advertisers and those working for them, Adap.tv may collect your IP address, Web pages that you visit, the time and date, and whether or not you clicked on various advertisements (collectively, "Web Surfing Data"). 

##### TECHNOLOGIES WE MAY USE FOR DATA COLLECTION.

Adap.tv and/or Adap.tv Associates use different types of technologies to collect non-personally-identifiable information, including cookies, action tags, Web beacons, and single pixel GIFs. Cookies. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes when you request through your browser to receive a particular Web page or content. Adap.tv uses cookies for three purposes.

_Persistent Cookies for Adap.tv Associates Use of Our Site._ For our Adap.tv Associates who login to our Site so that they may use our Services, Adap.tv utilizes persistent cookies to save your login information for future logins to the Site. This functionality works as it does on many websites that work to enable you to have an easier experience logging in and navigating their websites. We do not use persistent cookies in connection with helping Adap.tv Associates buy, sell, and deliver online video advertising.

_Session Cookies to Help Ad Delivery and Accounting._ Adap.tv utilizes session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Services, to better understand how you interact with the Services, and to monitor aggregate usage by Adap.tv users and Web traffic routing on the Services. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you close your browser.

_User Data Cookies for Ad Targeting._ Adap.tv utilizes cookies to store user data that can aid in targeting of advertisements. This data is usually collected by Adap.tv Associates and used to deliver advertisements that are more relevant to a user's interests.

_Use of Cookies By Others._ Also, the Web publisher or advertiser with whom we partner may use cookies, action tags, GIFs, or Web beacons to collect information when you are visiting their websites. The information they collect is governed by their individual privacy policies, not Adap.tv's. You are encouraged to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites that you visit. You can learn more about how cookies and related technologies are used in connection with online advertising and analytics by visiting: <http://www.aboutads.info/how-interest-based-ads-work>.

##### OPT-OUT PROCEDURE AND COOKIE CONTROL

Should you wish to opt-out of us placing a cookie on your browser, you can click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) to deploy an "opt-out" cookie on your browser. This cookie, when installed on your browser, will prevent us from placing a new cookie on that browser and from collecting data on that browser. The NAI's opt-out tool allows you to opt-out of the data collection and targeted ad programs of other NAI members. You may access the NAI opt-out tool [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Our opt-out tool and the NAI opt-out tool, are cookie-based. Both opt-out tools only prevent us from collecting data pertaining to you on the browser on which they are installed, and will only function if your browser is set to accept third-party cookies. If you delete an opt-out cookie from a browser's cookie files, we may collect data and place a new cookie unless an opt-out cookie is reset on that browser. If you block third-party cookies from being set on your browser, you may not be able to enjoy some features or functionality, and you may see the same content and advertisements repeatedly on some websites.

##### USE OF THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

_Use of Non-Personally-Identifiable Information._ The non-personally-identifiable data that Adap.tv and/or Adap.tv Associates collect when using the Services are used for marketing and sales efforts and to better target advertisements to people across the different websites they visit. Adap.tv may also use the non-personally-identifiable data that it collects to better target content to individuals in an effort to create a personally relevant experience for each person. The non-personally identifiable data is also used to predict responses to advertisements, and to help determine which ads perform best and which content is most appropriate for different individuals.

_Use of Personally-Identifiable Information._ Adap.tv uses personally-identifiable information it receives primarily to communicate with our Adap.tv Associates and Practices as we provide the Services. Adap.tv uses information we receive from business customer prospects in the same ways.

_Data from Adap.tv Associates._ Adap.tv allows Adap.tv Associates to import data that they have collected or purchased to deliver advertisements to certain audiences through the Services. Adap.tv is not responsible for and does not control the collection of this data. If you wish to opt out of collection of your information by third parties, then you must do so directly with those third parties.

_Health Related Segments._ We and our clients sometimes use health related targeting data segments provided by third party data companies, however these segments do not contain sensitive data (as described above). The non-sensitive health related data segments that can be used on our platform are in the following categories: (1) occupation in a health related field, (2) health related topics and conditions (but not specific conditions), (3) health insurance, (4) diet, fitness, weight-loss and healthy lifestyles, (5) consumer goods and services for personal healthcare, visioncare, grooming and beauty, (5) over the counter medicines, remedies and dietary supplements, and (6) health related charities. 

##### SHARING AND DISCLOSURE OF COLLECTED INFORMATION

Adap.tv does not provide personally-identifiable information to Adap.tv Associates or other third parties for their marketing purposes except under the following conditions.If a visitor to our Site provides personally-identifiable information as part of an inquiry about products or services provided by one of our Adap.tv Associates, we will provide that information only to that Adap.tv Associate so that they may attempt to respond to the inquiry.

Adap.tv may share Non-PII collected on Adap.tv or via our video advertising platform with unaffiliated third parties for our business purposes. We may also share user level Non-PII and aggregate Non-PII collected via our video advertising platform with unaffiliated third parties for our business purposes, including but not limited to enabling our business partners to help us target ads via the video advertising platform. This information cannot be used to contact or identify any person individually. Adap.tv may also disclose your information to third parties when obligated to do so by law and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected, or actual prohibited activities, including but not limited to fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person. 

Like most businesses, we will use information we receive for our business purposes and keep this information for as long as we have a legitimate business purpose as permitted by applicable law. Adap.tv may also disclose your information to third parties when obligated to do so by law and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected, or actual prohibited activities, including but not limited to fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person. 

_Service Providers._ Adap.tv may employ third-party companies and individuals to facilitate the Services, to provide the Services on our behalf, to perform website-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, Web analytics, and improvement of the Site's features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site and Services are used. These third parties have access to your personal information only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

_Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement._ Adap.tv may disclose information when necessary in cooperation with government and law enforcement officials or private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or to law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including, but not limited to subpoenas), or to protect Adap.tv's rights, property, or those of others.

_Business Transfers._ In addition to the above, there is also the possibility that Adap.tv may one day be purchased by, or merged with, another company or otherwise be reorganized or sold. If that's the case, the acquiring (or merging) company will have access to your information.

##### DATA RETENTION

The amount of time that we retain data we collect on our systems varies in length based on the type of data collected, but is only retained by us so long as necessary to fulfill our legitimate business needs. Specifically, we retain data as follows:

_Personal Information_

  * We retain account information obtained from vendors and business partners we work with indefinitely, but reserve the right to delete such information at our convenience.
  * Any personal information voluntarily provided to us via email communication or through our corporate website is maintained indefinitely until deleted by the corporate email account owner.

_Non-Personally Identifiable Information_

  * We retain click-stream data (such as IP address, date/time of visit, browser type, web pages visited, etc.) for up to thirteen (13) months. After thirteen (13) months, information may be stored in aggregate for statistical and analysis purposes or is deleted.
  * We retain behavioral segment data for periods as short as thirty (30) days, but may retain some behavioral segment data for up to thirteen (13) months. After thirteen (13) months, information may be stored in aggregate for statistical analysis purposes or is deleted.
  * We retain demographic data for periods as short as thirty (30) days, but may retain some demographic data for periods of five (5). After five (5) years, information may be stored in aggregate for statistical analysis purposes or is deleted.

##### SECURITY PRECAUTIONS

Adap.tv makes efforts to maintain the security of its network and the data we collect. We use various technologies, including, in certain instances, encryption, to ensure security standards. Adap.tv treats data that is stored on its servers as confidential information. Adap.tv has an internal security policy with respect to the confidentiality of customer and other data, limiting access only to those employees who we reasonably believe need to know such information for the purpose of performing their jobs. Please keep in mind, however, that the Internet is not a 100% secure medium. Therefore, although Adap.tv uses reasonable efforts to protect information, the possibility of somebody defeating its security measures does exist and none of our security measures should be viewed as a guarantee.

##### INTERNATIONAL VISITORS

Adap.tv is located in the United States of America, and the Site and Services are directed toward persons located within the United States of America. If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, including those whose privacy laws may be more strict than U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States to Adap.tv. If you choose to use the Adap.tv Site and/or Services, you understand and consent to the processing of your personal information in the United States.

##### LINKS TO WEB PUBLISHERS, ADVERTISERS, AND OTHER WEBSITES

Adap.tv's Services are combined with content from Adap.tv Associates and other third-party advertisers. Adap.tv's Services may contain links to other websites. If you choose to visit a Business Customer or other third-party advertiser by clicking on a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third-party link, you will be directed to that third-party's website. Our provision of a link to a website or a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement of that website or advertisement, nor is it an endorsement of the privacy or information security policies or practices of that website or advertiser. Adap.tv is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of Web publishers, advertisers, or other websites that may be linked to Adap.tv's Sites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, or solicit personal information from you. This Privacy Policy addresses the use and disclosure of information that we collect from you through our Services. Other websites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. You are encouraged to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

##### OUR POLICY TOWARD CHILDREN

This Site is not directed to children under 18. We do not knowingly collect personally-identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personally-identifiable information without their consent, he or she should contact Adap.tv at support@adap.tv.If Adap.tv becomes aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personally-identifiable information, Adap.tv will delete such information from our files.

##### ACCESSING YOUR PERSONALLY-IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION, MAKING CHANGES, OR REQUESTING DELETION

Where Adap.tv processes personally-identifiable information on our own behalf, you may request access to, correction of, or deletion of personal data held by us. If you desire to access such information we may hold, update the information, or for any privacy or data-protection-related question please write to: [support@adap.tv](mailto:support@adap.tv) for assistance. Because we generally process data for others, for any of that data you should make your request directly to the party collecting the information or on whose behalf it has been collected.

##### CONTACTING ADAP.TV

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should contact Adap.tv by sending email to [support@adap.tv](mailto:support@adap.tv) with "Privacy" in the subject line or you may write to:

Adap.tv, Inc.  
One Waters Park Drive  
Suite 250  
San Mateo, California 94403

##### ACCEPTANCE OF PRIVACY STATEMENT

Your use of the Site is subject to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use Agreement, which can be found here. BY USING OUR SITE, YOU ARE ACCEPTING THE PRACTICES SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND IN OUR TERMS OF USE AGREEMENT.

##### CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

Adap.tv reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the changes on the Site. Please check the effective date at the bottom of this page to determine if the Privacy Policy has been modified since you last reviewed it. In the event that any material changes are made to Adap.tv's privacy practices, we will notify you by posting the new Privacy Policy on the Site. You are advised to consult this Privacy Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued use of the Site and Services following posting of the updated Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the changes.

##### EFFECTIVE DATE

The Privacy Policy was last revised on 3/4/2014.
